早啊  妈
Morning, mom.
诶
Eh.
睡得不好吗
Tough night?
我晚上被孩子折腾起来三次
I had to get up three times with the baby
而你爹没帮一点儿忙
and your father was absolutely no help.
我帮了
Sure I was.
拍我脑门说
Flicking me in the forehead and saying
“孩子哭了”可不算帮忙
"baby's crying" is not helpful.
亲爱的  如果我光拍你的脑门
Honey, if I flicked you in the forehead and
而没说任何话  那就是我的不对了
didn't say anything, It's just being mean
嘿  吃完早饭后  能有人照顾下
Hey, after breakfast, if somebody watch
托比吗  我去洗个澡
Toby while I grab a shower?
噢  我不成
Oh, I can't.
我有个长满蛆的老鼠洞需要消灭
I have a maggot-infested rats' nest that needs my attention.
-拜  -拜
-Bye. -Bye.
抱歉了  妈  我想帮你  但我要和艾薇去趟商场
Sorry, mom. I'd love to, but I'm going to the mall with Ivy.
我们想买点儿东西  顺便找找工作
We're gonna shop and look for jobs.
主要还是买东西
Mostly shop.
再见
See you.
我要带查莉去公园玩
And I'm taking Charlie to the park.
哦  那你能不能也带托比一起去
Oh, maybe you can take Toby with you.
不用了  谢谢妈妈
No thank you, mama.
嗯
Hmm.
-再见  -再见
-Bye. -Bye.
盖比
Gabe?
不用了  谢谢妈妈
No thank you, mama.
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast </i>
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
■
翻译： Enpistu
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
■
校订： Johnny-Z
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
■
后期： Johnny-Z  liloelva
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好将来
<i>But I know your future's bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There's no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Your life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love</i> <i>who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第三季第十集
Good Luck Charlie  S03E10  Wentz's Weather Girls
好了  查莉  走了啊  玩去吧
Okay, Charlie. Here we go. Have fun.
别骑太快
Not too fast.
别骑太快  她可是整个公园骑得最快的小孩
Not too fast. She's already the fastest kid in the park.
如果你想见识什么是真正的快
If you want to see fast, you should
先看看我侄子梅森是怎么骑车的
see my nephew Mason ride his trike.
你知道他的朋友都称呼他什么吗
You know what his friends call him?
-什么  -什么也没有
-What? -Nothing.
他骑得太快  根本没时间交朋友
He's so fast, he doesn't have time to make friends.
啊  好吧  查莉骑得那么快
Yeah, well, Charlie's so fast,
呃  而且她也交到了朋友
that.. that she makes friends.
但是一旦她走远了  再回来的时候
But then she goes so far, by the time she
他们都已经不在原来的位置了
comes back they've changed their move on...
然后  我真是编不下去了
And.. I am really not good at this.
反正重点是  梅森更快
The point is, Mason's faster.
不  查莉更快
No. Charlie's faster.
你知道这让我想起什么了吗
You know what this reminds me of?
咱们以前也谈过宝贝赛跑的话题
The conversation that we had before the baby race.
哦  宝贝赛跑啊
Oh. The baby race.
加油  查莉  你能行的
Come on, Charlie, you can do it.
比赛正在进入白热化阶段  现在依然是梅森领先
Coming down the home stretch, it's still Mason in the lead!
加油啊  查莉  这是最后的机会
Come on, Charlie. It's now or never!
胜利者是  查莉
And the winner is Charlie!
好吧
Okay.
或许查莉的脚程更胜一筹  但说到骑车
Charlie may be faster on her feet, but on wheels?
梅森才是赢家
Mason's the man.
我猜要搞清楚这件事只有一种方法了
Guess there's only one way to find out.
你想说的是不是跟我不谋而合啊
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
宝贝赛跑第二轮
Baby race two.
帝国三轮车反击战
The empire trikes back!
你好啊  爸
Hey, dad.
温兹叔叔好
Hi, Mr. Wentz.
我们要去商场买东西  顺便找工作
We're going to the mall to shop and look for jobs..
但主要是买东西
But mostly shop.
-钱包在那边  -我能拿多少钱
-Wallet's over there. -How much can I take?
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
什么都无所谓
Nothing matters.
艾薇  你爸怎么会这样没精神
Ivy, why is your dad so depressed?
不知道啊
I don't know.
估计又是工作上的事让他不顺心了呗
I think it might be something about his job.
-他做什么工作  -不知道啊
-What does he do? -I don't know.
艾薇  你现在不许去商场
Ivy, you're not going to the mall
先去把你的房间收拾好  快去
without cleaning your room, are you?
哦  哈利  亲爱的  搞不懂你干嘛要闷闷不乐
Oh, Harry, honey. I don't know why you're so down.
快给泰迪看看你昨天晚上得的那个奖
Show Teddy the award you got last night.
这是银揣子奖
That's the silver plungie.
这是对哈利二十五年来都在
It's in recognition of Harry's 25 years
干疏通管道这一行的嘉奖
in the plumbing supply business.
哦  恭喜你  温兹叔叔  这真是太荣幸了
Oh, congratulations, Mr. Wentz. That is quite an honor.
可不是吗  上头还有致辞呢  看见没有
Well, I think so. It even has an inscription. see?
说“致哈利·温兹  勤恳工作25年”
It says, "to harry wentz, for 25 years of duty".
（注：Duty也有去厕所的意思）
呃  这真是不幸啊
Well, that's unfortunate.
哦  我得找个地儿把它供起来
Oh, I'm gonna go find a place for it.
难道我二十五年来就
Is this all I have to show..
只有这玩意儿可展示吗
For 25 years of my life?
就这个漆成银色的皮揣子
A plunger that they spray-painted silver.
它还是很炫的
It's glittery, too.
我也是有过梦想的
I used to have dreams.
伟大的梦想
Big dreams.
我梦想成为
I wanted to be..
一个气象预报员
A weatherman.
我还想过开一家自己的餐馆
I wanted to open a restaurant.
但是
But..
我已经老了  这两个梦都来不及了
I'm too old for any of that now.
温兹叔叔  追求梦想永远不会太迟
Mr. Wentz, you are never too old to pursue your dreams.
哦  泰迪  我不知道
Oh, Teddy, I don't know.
你看到那家新开的健身中心打出的广告了吗
Have you seen that commercial for the new fitness centers?
那个有会说话地鼠的广告吗
The one with the talking gophers?
没错  瘦地鼠是这么对胖地鼠说的
Right. The skinny gopher says to the fat gopher..
“如果你想减肥  你就
"If you want to lose that weight, you
别老坐着  千里之行始于足下”
gotta get off your butt and go for it.
的确  这广告词有点意思
Sure, it's a terrific commercial.
但你想表达什么嘞
But what's your point?
那就是你前进的方向  温兹叔叔
That's what you gotta do, Mr. Wentz.
要跟随你的梦想  并勇往直前  就像地鼠那样
You gotta follow your dreams and "gopher" it!
（注：“勇往直前”与“地鼠”谐音）
像地鼠那样
"Gopher" it.
你干嘛打扮成这样
Why are you dressed like that?
因为我根本没时间洗衣服
Because I haven't had a chance to do the laundry.
信不信由你  我穿的是你的T恤  你爹的运动裤
Believe it or not, this is your shirt, your dad's sweats,
恐怕你不想知道我穿的是谁的裤衩
And you don't even want to know whose underwear I have on.
-PJ的  -你怎么知道
-They're PJ's. -You don't know that.
我看见松紧带上有蝙蝠侠的脑袋
I can see batman's head on the waistband.
这是什么味道
What is that smell?
这是我的新香水
That's my new body spray.
你看看
Check it out.
“哥们儿”
"Duude".
还加个儿化音
With two "u"s.
即将十三岁的酷小伙专用香水
Body spray for cool dudes ages 12 to 13.
你准备这些是为了什么
What's all this about?
什么也不为
Nothing.
哦  顺便说一下  接下来的几天
Oh, and by the way, for the next couple of days,
我要和我暑期班的一个同学
I'm gonna be working on a project
一起做一个作业
with a kid from summer school.
哦  我懂了  这个同学是男同学还是女同学啊
Oh, I see. Is this kid a boy kid or a girl kid?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
我在学校的时候对功课太专心了
When I'm at school I'm all about the work.
噢
Aw.
我的小宝贝恋爱了
My little baby has a crush.
亲爱的  我能帮上你什么忙吗
Honey, can I give you some advice?
我已经十三了  再也不需要我妈的任何帮助
I'm 13 now. I don't need any help from my mommy.
我说的是“哥们儿”的广告词
That's a direct quote from the "Duude" commercial.
出去
Get out!
好吧
Okay.
我打扮得漂漂亮亮  什么也不为
I got all dressed up for nothing?
你好  盖比
Hi, Gabe.
你好  简德
Hi, Jade.
我喜欢来你家玩
I like hanging out at your house.
你家永远是那么的安静合乐
It's always so nice and pieceful.
你干了什么  连商量都没跟我商量过
You did what?! Without even asking me?
哈利  你给我回来
Harry, you come back here!
姑娘们  我有个激动人心的消息
Girls, I have some exciting news.
你爸辞了工作  拿咱们家
Your father quit his job, took our
过日子的钱  盘了一家餐馆
life savings, and bought a restaurant.
我把两个梦想合二为一  创建了
I combined both my passions and created
全世界第一家天气主题餐厅
the world's first weather themed eatery.
飓风哈利气象餐厅
Hurricane Harry's weather cafe.
这全是托泰迪的福
And I owe it all to teddy.
为什么是我
What did I do?
你教他这个
You did this.
我们全都要在那里工作
And we're all gonna work there.
我  为什么我也要
Me? What did I do?
你不是想找工作吗  现在工作来了
Well, you wanted jobs? Now you got them.
-不用了  温兹先生  -哦  不不不  泰迪
-That's okay, Mr. Wentz.. -Oh, no, no, no, no, Teddy.
你也得加入进来
You are going to be a part of this, too.
就是因为你  这个家庭
Because of you, this family is
已经搭上一辆疯狂列车了
taking a ride on a crazy train.
无人幸免
All aboard.
呜-呜
Woo-woo.
嗯
Hmm.
啊
Ah.
好了
Okay.
查莉  我做了一些改装
Charlie, I've made some adjustments.
现在你的车更符合空气动力学了
Your trike is now more airdynamic.
我的车铃呢
Where's my bell?
哦  你不需要车铃
Oh, you don't need a bell,
你会一路保持领先的
you'll be in front all the time.
对吗
Right?
很好
Yes.
好啊  好啊  你是来反悔的吗
Well, well, well. You here to back out?
不  我来是为了先让你看看
No, I'm here to show you a preview of what
明天比赛之后给你准备的节目
you're gonna see tomorrow after the race.
我的胜利之舞
My victory dance.
哈  你喜欢吗
Uh! You like that?
-就这样  -是啊
-Oh yeah? -Yeah.
很好  我也准备了胜利之舞
Well, I got a victory dance, too.
-在哪呢  -就像这样  走着
-Where's it at? -Goes a little something like this.
还不错  喜欢吗
That's okay, you like this?
哦  赞
Oh, yes.
好了  大家伙  我们五分钟后就开张了
All right, everybody, we open in five minutes.
自然母亲呢
Where's mother nature?
我在这儿
Here I am.
哦  玛丽露  你可真迷人
Oh, Mary Lou, you look stunning.
哦  你知道吗
Oh, you know what?
我还以为这样会很傻呢  但是我必须承认
I thought this would be silly, but I must say..
这角色非我莫属
I do make it work.
好吧  我的特别服务生在哪
All right, where are my special waitresses?
阳光和雨露
Sunny and cloudy?
在这儿呢
Here we are.
那个
So..
要上暑期班真是倒霉透了  是不是
Kind of a bummer having to go to summer school, right?
我挺喜欢暑期班的
I like summer school.
我也是
Me too.
我说倒霉的时候  其实意思是  倒霉
When I said bummer, I meant bummer!
你只是换个口气说一个词
You can't change the meaning of a
是改变不了它的意思的
word by just saying it differently.
倒霉
Bummer.
嗯
Um..
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
嘿
Hey.
进展怎么样了  帅哥
How's it going out there, tiger?
糟透了  我一直在说错话
Terrible. I keep saying the wrong thing.
好吧
Well.
我知道你怎样可以赢得她的心
I know how you can win her over
而且你一个字都不用说
without saying a single word.
小宝宝  他要怎么帮我啊
The baby? How is he gonna help me?
一旦她看到你和托比相处得有多好
Once she sees how great you are with Toby..
她准会着迷得心都化了
She is guaranteed to melt.
现在
Now..
好好抱着他
Hold him close.
晃晃他的小脑袋
Cradle the head.
希望你能比我大哥更懂得怎么和女孩相处
I hope you're better with girls than my older brother.
简德  你还没见过我的婴儿小弟弟吧
Jade, I don't think you've met my baby brother.
这是托比
This is Toby.
哦天啊  他好可爱
Oh my gosh, he's so cute.
你和他相处的真好
And you're so good with him.
技巧是晃他的脑袋
The trick is to cradle the head.
来  再加点雨吧
Here, have some more rain.
也就是水啦
That's what we call water.
是不是很好玩啊
Isn't that fun?
马丁  四人桌  你们的座位准备好了
Martin, party of four, your table is ready.
我是飓风哈利  来做特别公告
This is hurricane Harry with a special bulletin.
接下来几分钟的预报是余兴节目
The forecast for the next few minutes is entertaining.
女士们先生们  音乐表演来自
Ladies and gentlemen, the musical stylings of..
温兹气象女孩
Wentz's weather girls.
来吧
Hit it.
飓风哈利好地方  滴嘀嗒嗒
Hurricane Harry's is the spot doo-dah, doo-dah.
我们供应菜肴  冷冷热热  无论白天
We serve our dishes cold and hot all the doo-dah day.
与黑夜
And night!
温兹气象女孩
Wentz's weather girls.
她们每个小时都会回来再表演一次
And they'll be back to do it again every hour on the hour.
如果我不知道这事是我爹干的  我会更喜欢
I liked it better when I didn't know what my dad did.
你觉得我们晾得够干了  能进屋了吗
Think we're dry enough to go in yet?
不行
Nope.
依然湿嗒嗒
Still squishing.
嘿
Hey.
上一场暴风雨里是什么东西在砸我们  冰雹吗
What hit us during that last storm? Was that sleet?
不是  熊孩子把一碗玉米片扔进电扇里了
No. Kid threw a bowl of nachos into the fan.
咱得辞了这份工作
We gotta quit this job.
我们不能啊  你妈会杀了我
We can't. Your mom would kill me
而你爸会垮掉的
and your dad will be crushed.
好吧  如果他明天再加上个地震
Well, if he adds an earthquake tomorrow,
咱俩才会真正的垮掉
we might actually be crushed.
等等  咱们虽然不能辞职
Wait, we can't quit.
但是可以被开除
But we could get fired.
有了
Yeah.
哦  虽然不知道你想到啥主意  但是我喜欢
Ooh, I don't know what you're thinking, but I like it.
嘿  咱们休息一下怎么样  你介意吗
Hey, do you mind if we take a break for a second?
为什么
Why?
其实就是  我要为我弟弟做件事情
There's just this thing I do for my baby brother.
我要与他分享人生课程  并提出建议
I share life lessons and give him advice.
我称之为视频日记
I call it a video diary.
这真是最最贴心的事儿了
That is the sweetest thing ever.
我常这么做啦
I get that a lot.
嘿  查
Hey, Char..
托比
Toby.
我是你大哥盖比
It's your big brother Gabe here with
正在录另一段超凡的视频日记
another one of my signature video diary.
昨天晚上我给你掖好被子
Anyway, last night after I tucked
亲吻你额头之后
you in and kissed you in your head.
为你唱着摇篮曲  直到你睡着
I sang you to sleep with a song.
哦  你现在能再唱一下吗
Oh, can you sing it now?
求你了
Please?
呃
Um.
安静  小托比要睡觉
Hush, little Toby go to sleep.
已经睡着了就接着睡觉
You're already asleep so stay asleep.
啦啦啦  啦啦啦  啦啦啦
La-la-la la-la-la la-la-la.
睡觉
Sleep.
睡觉觉  睡觉觉  睡觉  睡觉  睡觉
Sleepy sleep, sleepy sleep sleep, sleep, sleep.
噢
Aw.
好了  这次录够了  接下来  我会说
Well, that's all for now, so, I'll just say..
祝你
Good..
幸运  小托比
Fortune, Toby.
这算是我的个人特色
That's sort of my trademark.
好了  要记住  查莉  求胜不是一切
Now, remember, Charlie. Winning isn't everything.
-是唯一  -对  就是这样
-It's the only thing. -Yes. Yes.
好了  还记得过去两年你背负的耻辱吗
Okay, you know that shame you felt for the last two years?
今天就要结束了
It ends today.
还是会耻上加耻就看你这次表现了
Or it could get worse depending on how this goes.
好了
Okay.
赛程是从这里骑到那个灯柱  再折回来
The race is to that lamppost and back.
第一个通过终点线的车手获胜
First trike to cross the finish line wins.
获什么胜
Wins what?
-你好啊  爸  -怎么回事
-Hey, dad. -What is going on?
没事
Nothing.
我们就在公园里走走
We're just hanging out at the park.
那让孩子们带着那些号码干嘛
Then why have the kids got numbers on them?
因为我俩正在教他们学数数
Because we're teaching them their ones and twos.
这件事咱们都说了多少次了
How many times have we been over this?
你们不能像赛马一样让孩子比赛
You cannot race children like horses.
那像赛狗一样可以吗
Can we race them like dogs?
根本就不能让他们比赛
You can't race them at all.
行了  孩子们  过来  嘿
All right, kids, come on. Hey,
有谁想去游乐场玩
who wants to go the playground.
嗯  好了  走吧
Huh? Okay, come on.
真是的
Man!
我已经马力全开  就等今天的比赛了
I was all fired up for a race today.
是啊  我也一样
Yeah, me too.
我们依然可以赛一赛  你懂的
You know, we could still have a race.
托比呢
Where's Toby?
你爸带他去公园了
Dad took him to the park.
什么
What?
哦不  简德要走了  我得做出下一步行动
No, no, Jade's about to leave and I need to make a move.
那就走你的下一步啊
So make your move.
我没有棋子
I don't have a move.
我需要托比  她喜欢看我和托比其乐融融的样子
I need Toby.. she likes it when I do nice things for him.
盖比  我走了
Gabe, I'm leaving.
等等
Wait!
嘿
Hey.
那个
So..
嗯
Um..
呃
Uh..
我就是想问问
I was just wondering if..
你愿意有时间和我一起去看个电影吗
You wanted to go to a movie with me sometime?
哦
Oh..
嗯
Um..
不必了  谢谢
No, thank you.
可是  我还以为你对我有点好感呢
But I thought you were kinda into me?
的确  作为普通朋友
Yeah, as a friend but..
但我是不会和你约会的
I could never date you.
我喜欢坏小子
I like bad boys.
啥  可我就是个坏小子啊
Wha.. but I am a bad boy.
那些哄小孩的把戏我都是闹着玩的
I was just kidding about all that baby stuff.
盖比  你应该为自己感到自豪
Gabe, be proud of who you are.
你是个温柔  敏感  善良的男孩
A sweet, sensitive, good boy.
不  我不是  我是个十足的混蛋  你问别人
No. I'm not. I'm a total jerk, ask anyone.
小甜心
Sweetie-pie.
这块你亲手给宝宝织的毯子实在是
This blanket you knit for the baby is..
无价之宝啊
Absolutely precious.
再见  盖比
Bye, Gabe.
哇
Whoa!
噢耶  太棒了
Woo! Yes! Yes!
瞧着吧
Watch this!
好了  即将进入本钟头的高潮
Well, that brings us to the top of
也就是说  又是轮到
the hour which means it is time
温兹气象女孩上场的时候了
To give it up again for wentz's weather girls.
做好被炒的准备了吗
You ready to get fired?
来吧
Hit it.
这可真是个坏主意啊
I guess that was a bad idea.
我们把一切都毁了
We've ruined everything.
如果你不得不做出艰难的选择  我们可以理解
If you have to make some tough choices, we understand.
我是在说开除我们的事
And I'm talking about firing us.
这真是
That was..
太给力了
Awesome!
我的气象女孩
My weather girls.
我们要永永远远在一起
We are going to be together forever.
哦  你猜怎么着
Well, what do you know.
孩子们
My boys.
好啊
Yeah.
他刚睡醒一觉  我逗他玩会儿
He woke up from his nap so we're just hanging out.
哦
Oh.
你知道托比让我想到谁了吗
You know who Toby reminds me of?
就是你
You.
因为他没有女朋友吗
Because he doesn't have a girlfriend?
不是
No.
因为你们俩的眼睛里都会擦出火花
Because you both have that sparkle in your eyes.
那是另一样姑娘们喜欢的东西
And that's another thing girls like..
火花
A sparkle.
谢谢  老妈
Thanks, mom.
嗯  既然有你在照看托比  你不介意
Well, since you're watching toby, you don't,
呃  不介意我去打个盹儿吧
um, mind if I take a nap, do you?
那  那好吧  但是如果他
Well, I.. I guess, but if he..
老妈
Mom?
你好啊  托比  我是你哥盖比
Hey, Toby. Gabe here.
在此  我要告诉你
So, I want to tell you everything
我所学到关于女孩子的一切
that I've learned about girls.
没错
That's it.
不管怎样  如果你未来需要什么建议
Anyway, if you ever need any advice in the future..
等一下  你  你在干什么
Wait. what.. what are you doing?
为托比录视频日记
Making a video diary for Toby.
啥  这可是我的事儿
Wha.. that's kind of my thing.
不再是了
Not any more.
那么
So..
下回我再喜欢上一个女孩子的时候
The next time I have a crush on a
祝我幸运吧  小托比
girl, wish me good furtune, Toby.
哦  你开什么玩笑啊
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
你嫉妒了
Jealous?
什么  才不呢  我是纳闷
What? No. Confused. What does
“祝你幸运  小托比”是怎么回事
"Good fortune,Toby." Even mean.
意思是小托比足够幸运用不着听你说
It means that Toby has the good fortune
“祝你好运啰  小查莉”
not to hear "Good luck, Charlie."
够了  把我的摄像机还来
Okay, give me my camera.
祝你幸运  托比
Good fortune, Toby.
祝你好运  查莉
Good luck, Charlie.
呼  骑的真爽
Woo. What a ride.
你知道吗  经过那样的剧烈运动之后
You know, after a workout like that,
我可不想再洗什么泡泡浴了
I don't want some kind of kiddie bubble bath.
我已经快十三岁了
I'm 12 to 13 now.
我使用的香水要和我本人一样劲爆
I want a body spray that works as hard as I do.
因此我选择“哥们儿”
That's why I use "Duude".
哥们儿  当你不再需要来自妈妈的任何帮助
Duude, when you don't need help from your mommy any more.
哥们儿  来自“小伙儿”和“老兄”的制造商
Duude, from the makers of "Guy" and "Bro".